# **Subhankar Rout**

**User Experience Designer | Product Designer** 



Watch My Video CV

- **+91 9337663465**
- subhankarrout.kiit@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/subhankarrout
- www.subhankarrout.in/portfolio

# **Profile Summary**

As a UI/UX Designer, I merge creativity with technical expertise to craft engaging designs, leading numerous projects that boost user satisfaction by an average of 30%. My collaborative efforts with 100+ professionals yield innovative designs that resonate deeply with users, reflecting a commitment to excellence in user experience.

# **Experience**

#### Senior User Experience Designer

Deligence Technologies Inc. | Jan 2024 - Present

- As a Senior UI/UX Designer, I revamped a leading educational game's UI/UX, increasing user engagement by 20%, and reduced user drop-off rates by 15%.
- My tasks include designing wireframes, prototypes, user research and user flows to enhance the overall user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate user feedback into design iterations, resulting in a user satisfaction score increase of 30%.

#### Visual Interaction Designer

RPATech, Gurugram | Oct 2020 - January 2024

- As a Visual Interaction Designer, I developed engaging visual content for top-rated online courses, resulting in a 40% increase in course enrollment on platforms like Coursera and Udemy.
- Crafted user interfaces and experiences for our Robotic Process Automation (RPA) projects.
- Enhanced learning experiences through collaborative stakeholder engagement and effective design solutions.

#### **Certifications**

## **Project Management Professional Certification**

Atlassian, Aha! and IIBA | 2024

 Develop a deep understanding of Product life cycle management, roadmaps and Agile Project Management

# **UX Design Professional Certification**

Google LLP | 2023

Learned to conduct research, white boarding, and prototype creation in UX Design.

#### **User Experience Designer Certification Course**

LinkedIn Learning | 2021

Gained skills in using UI/UX tools for designing and prototyping user interfaces.

## Brand Management: Aligning Business, Brand and Behavior

London Business School | 2021

• Learned to align brand strategy with product development.

# How to ChatGPT: Master the Art of Prompt Engineering

Udemy Learning | 2023

• Learned prompt engineering and how to effectively use ChatGPT.

# **Education**

#### GIET University, Gunupur

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering | 2017 - 2021

## **Skills**

#### Design

 $\label{eq:User_Experience} User\ Experience \cdot Interaction\ Design \cdot User\ Interface \cdot Prototyping \cdot Visual\ Design \cdot Wireframing \cdot Mockups\ Design$ 

#### Research

 $\label{local-problem} User\ Interviews \cdot User\ Testing \cdot Design\ System \cdot Information \\ Architecture \cdot Journey\ Mapping \cdot Quantitative\ Analysis \cdot A/B\ Testing \cdot Competitor\ Analysis \cdot Brand\ Strategy$ 

#### Software

 $\label{eq:proposed_$ 

## Visual Design

Poster Design  $\cdot$  Branding  $\cdot$  Typography  $\cdot$  Iconography  $\cdot$  Book Design  $\cdot$  App Design  $\cdot$  Web Design, Stylesheets and Guidelines

# Methodologies

Scrum · Alige · Waterfall (PM) · Design Thinking (Product Design)

#### Other Skills

 ${\it Collaboration \ and \ Communication \cdot Team \ Management \cdot Project} \\ {\it Management \cdot Stakeholder \ Management}$ 

# **Achievements**

UI Design Excellence - Deligence Technologies Inc. | 2024
Appreciation for fast learning and Implementations - DT | 2024
Annual Excellence Award by CEO - RPATech | 2022
Creativity and Innovation Recognition by AVP - RPATech | 2021
Innovation Challenge Runners-up - IEEE GIETU | 2020
Filmmaker Champion - NSS MBD Camp | 2019
Best Filmmaker Award - GIET University | 2018

# **Extra-curricular Activities**

- Authored a published English novel, showcasing creativity and storytelling skills.
- Recognized by the Commissioner of Municipality, Rourkela, for contributions to literature and culture.
- Featured in news outlets for both novel and music albums.
- Created and managed the "S4 Cinesphere" YouTube channel, producing music albums and short films during college.

# Language

#### English, Hindi, Odia

(Proficient in understanding, writing, and speaking)